Guide to the Ira Vaughan Hiscock Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
The files in Series III. were apparently kept by the secretary of the Department of Public Health, who had developed a code for filing the papers of individual faculty members. General routine correspondence concerning social engagements and requests for reprints were filed in code "b". Code "h" was established for material concerning Hiscock's military service and includes notices of reserve meetings, assignment sheets, and committee meeting announcements. Speaking engagements, code "d", includes invitations, responses, and some speech texts. Of particular interest are Hiscock's remarks, on the 1954 acceptance of the Massachusetts Public Health Association's Lemuel Shattuck Medal and Certificate (folder 1672) and the A.P.H.A.'s 1962 Sedgwick Memorial Award (folder 1577). In the 1972 correspondence file (folder 1558) are messages to Hiscock on the occasion of a dinner in his honor. Code "e", Writings, documents the establishment of two commemorative awards in Hiscock's honor, the New England Public Health Association's Ira V. Hiscock Award, first presented in 1974, and the Ira V. Hiscock Lecture at the Yale School of Medicine, first delivered by Sir George Godber in 1975 (folder 1610).
The Ira V. Hiscock Papers were donated to Yale University Library by the Department of Public Health of the Yale School of Medicine in 1971. The papers are part of the Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection. Additional material concerning Hiscock is included in the records of the Department of Epidemiology and Public Health, YRG27.
Biographical / Historical
Bacteriologist; member of the Conn. Dept. of Health, 1914-1917; from 1920-1960, professor of public health, Yale University; innovator in the areas of public health surveys and state and local health councils; frequent consultant and volunteer to local, state, and national social welfare agencies.
Bacteriology; Child health services; Communicable diseases; Dairy farming -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Health education; Health maintenance organizations -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Health surveys; Health insurance; Maternal health services; Mental health; Milk -- Pasteurization; Public health -- Connecticut; Sanitation; Sex instruction; Tuberculosis; Voluntary health agencies -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Water -- Purification; New Haven (Conn.); Bacteriologists; Educators; Health-officers; Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection; Atwater, Reginald Myers, 1892-1957; Bauer, Walter W., 1898-1963; Baumgartner, Leona, 1902-1991; Bigelow, George Hoyt, 1890-; Borst, Homer Wiltsie; Bundesen, Herman N. (Herman Niels), 1882-1960; Claver, Homer Northup, 1892-1970; Davis, Michael M. (Michael Marks), 1879-1971; Dawson, John B., 1932-; Douglas, William O. (William Orville), 1898-1980; Draper, W. F. (Warren Fales), 1883-1970; Dublin, Louis I. (Louis Israel), 1882-1969; Emerson, Haven, 1874-1957; Emerson, Kendall, 1875-1962; Falk, I. S. (Isidore Sydney), 1899-1984; Galdston, Iago, 1895-; Galt, John Randolph, 1867-1941; Halverson, Wilton Lee; Hiscock, Ira V. (Ira Vaughan), 1892-; Kingsbury, John Adams, 1876-1956; Knowlton, Millard; Mangold, Walter S.; Marquette, Bleeker; Mickle, Friend Lee, 1889-1978; Osborn, Stanley Hart, 1924-; Palmer, George T. (George Truman), 1887-1971; Patterson, Raymond Sears; Platt, Philip Skinner, 1889-; Rice, John L.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919; Routzahn, Evart Grant, 1869-; Scamman, Clarence L.; Sigerist, Henry E. (Henry Ernest), 1891-1957; Snow, William Freeman, 1874-1950; Sydenstricker, Edgar, 1881-1936; Tobey, James A. (James Alner), 1894-1980; Vaughan, Henry F. (Henry Frieze), 1889-1979; Walker, Warren F. (Warren Franklin); Widdemer, Kenneth D.; Winslow, C.-E. A. (Charles-Edward Amory), 1877-1957; New Haven (Conn.). Department of Health; New York (N.Y.). Department of Health; American Child Health Association; American Public Health Association; American Social Hygiene Association; Boy Scouts of America; Boy Scouts of America. New Haven Council; Boy Scouts of America. Quinnipiac Council; Cancer Control Committee of New Haven; Chamber of Commerce (New Haven, Conn.); Commonwealth Fund; Community Chest (New Haven, Conn.); Connecticut Society for Mental Hygiene. New Haven Chapter; Connecticut. State Department of Health; Council of Social Agencies (New Haven, Conn.); Family Service of New Haven; Health Councils Executives' Association; Milbank Memorial Fund; National Health Council (U.S.); National Organization for Public Health Nursing (U.S.); National Tuberculosis Association; State Charities Aid Association (N.Y.); Visiting Nurse Association (New Haven, Conn.); Yale University. Department of Epidemiology and Public Health; Connecticut Conference of Social Work; National Conference on Social Work; National Health Council; White House Conference on Child Health and Protection
- OFFICE FILES, 1918-1924; Series I; 1 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  OFFICE FILES, 1918-1924, is arranged in chronological order.
  - 1918 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1921 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1921: New Haven dairy study (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1921: Writings (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1922 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1923 January-July (Box 1, Folder 7-13)
  - 1923 August-December (Box 2, Folder 14-18)
  - 1924 (Box 2, Folder 19-30)
- OFFICE FILES, 1925-1939; Series II; 32.5 linear feet (78 boxes)
  OFFICE FILES, 1925-1939, is divided chronologically by year. The files for a particular year are divided into: General Papers, Surveys, and Writings. Files in General Papers and Surveys are arranged alphabetically. Writings is arranged chronologically.
  - 1925 General Papers
    - A (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - American Child Health Association (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - American Public Health Association (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - American Social Hygiene Association (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - B (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - C (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Connecticut, State of (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Connecticut, State of, Department of Health (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - D-E (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - F (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - G (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - H (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - I-L (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - International Association of Dairy and Milk Inspectors (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - M (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - N (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - New England Health Institute, Portland, Maine (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - O-P (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - R-T (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - U (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - United States Treasury Department, Public Health Service (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - V-W (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Worcester, Massachusetts (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Yale University (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - 1925 Writings (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - 1926 General Papers
    - A (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - American Child Health Association (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - American Public Health Association. (Box 4, Folder 59-64)
    - B (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - C (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Connecticut, State of (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Connecticut, State of, Department of Health (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - D (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - E (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Emerson, Haven (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - G (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - H (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Hancock (John) Mutual Life Insurance Company (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - International Association of Dairy and Milk Inspectors, Committee on the Food Value of Milk (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - K-L (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - M (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - N (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - National Dairy Council (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - New Haven, A-Z (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - New Haven, City of (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - New Haven Community Chest (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - New Haven Visting Nurse Association (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - O-P (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - R (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - S (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - United States Treasury Department, Public Health Service (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - V (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - W (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Wesleyan University (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Yale University (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - 1926 Writings (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - 1927 General Papers
    - A (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - American Child Health Association (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - American Epidemiological Society (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - American Public Health Association (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - B (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Brookline, Massachusetts (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - C (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Connecticut, A-Z (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Connecticut Society for Mental Hygiene, New Haven branch (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Connecticut, State of (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Connecticut, State of, Commissioner on Domestic Animals (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Connecticut, State of, Department of Health (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - D-G (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - H (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - K (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - L (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - M (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Massachusetts, State of, Department of Education (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Massachusetts, State of, Department of Public Health (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - N (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - National Dairy Council (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - National Organization for Public Health Nursing (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - New Haven, A-Z (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - New Haven Community Chest (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - New Haven Organized Charities Association (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - New Haven Visiting Nurse Association (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - New Jersey, State of, Department of Health (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - O (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - P (Box 5, Folder 120)
    - R (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 6, Folder 122)
    - S (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - T (Box 6, Folder 124)
    - United States, A-Z (Box 6, Folder 125)
    - V (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - W (Box 6, Folder 127)
    - Wesleyan University (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - Winslow, C.-E. A. (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - Yale University, A-Z (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - Yale University, School of Medicine (Box 6, Folder 131-132)
      - Restricted, 1927 (Box 87)
        Conditions Governing Access
        Materials are restrcited until January 1, 2032.
  - 1927 Surveys
    - Arkansas Flood Relief (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company, Yale Athletes Mortality Study (Box 6, Folder 134)
  - 1928 General Papers
    - A (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - American Child Health Association (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - American Epidemiological Society (Box 6, Folder 137)
    - American Medical Association (Box 6, Folder 138)
    - American Public Health Association (Box 6, Folder 139-145)
    - American Social Hygiene Association (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - B (Box 7, Folder 147)
    - Boy Scouts of America, New Haven Council (Box 7, Folder 148)
    - C (Box 7, Folder 149)
    - California, State of (Box 7, Folder 150)
    - Columbia University (Box 7, Folder 151)
    - Commonwealth Fund (Box 7, Folder 152)
    - Connecticut Conference of Social Work (Box 7, Folder 153)
    - Connecticut, State of, Department of Health (Box 7, Folder 154)
    - D (Box 7, Folder 155)
    - Davis, Michael M. (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - E (Box 7, Folder 157)
    - G (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - H (Box 7, Folder 159)
    - I (Box 7, Folder 160)
    - Johns Hopkins University (Box 7, Folder 161)
    - Joint Vocational Service, Inc. (Box 7, Folder 161)
    - K (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - L (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - Los Angeles, County of (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - Los Angeles, County of, Department of Health (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - M (Box 7, Folder 166)
    - Massachusetts, State of, Department of Public Health (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - N (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - National Conference of Social Work (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - National Organization for Public Health Nursing (Box 7, Folder 170-171)
    - National Tuberculosis Association (Box 7, Folder 172)
    - New Haven, A-Z (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - New Haven, City of, Board of Health (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - New Haven Community Chest (Box 7, Folder 175)
    - New Haven, Organized Charities Association (Box 8, Folder 176)
    - New Haven Visiting Nurse Association (Box 8, Folder 177)
    - New York, State of, Department of Health (Box 8, Folder 178)
    - New York Tuberculosis and Health Association, Inc. (Box 8, Folder 179)
    - O (Box 8, Folder 180)
    - P (Box 8, Folder 181)
    - Public Health Federation (Box 8, Folder 182)
    - R (Box 8, Folder 183)
    - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 8, Folder 184)
    - Russell Sage Foundation (Box 8, Folder 185)
    - S (Box 8, Folder 186)
    - T (Box 8, Folder 187)
    - Tennessee, State of, Department of Health (Box 8, Folder 188)
    - United States, A-Z (Box 8, Folder 189)
    - United States Army (Box 8, Folder 190)
    - United States Department of Labor (Box 8, Folder 191)
    - V-W (Box 8, Folder 192)
    - Wesleyan University (Box 8, Folder 193)
    - Winslow, Anne R. (Mrs. C.-E. A.) (Box 8, Folder 194)
    - Winslow, C.-E. A. (Box 8, Folder 195)
    - Yale University, A-Z (Box 8, Folder 196)
    - Yale University, School of Medicine (Box 8, Folder 197-199)
  - 1928 Surveys
    - California, Los Angeles and Pasadena surveys (Box 8, Folder 200)
    - Honolulu study (Box 9, Folder 201)
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company, Yale Athletes Mortality Study (Box 9, Folder 202-204)
  - 1929 General Papers
    - A (Box 9, Folder 205)
    - American Child Health Association (Box 9, Folder 206)
    - American Epidemiological Society (Box 9, Folder 207)
    - American Public Health Association (Box 9, Folder 208-214)
    - American Public Health Association (Box 10, Folder 215-217)
    - American Social Hygiene Association (Box 10, Folder 218)
    - B (Box 10, Folder 219)
    - Bellevue-Yorkville Health Demonstration (Box 10, Folder 220)
    - Boy Scouts of America, New Haven Council (Box 10, Folder 221-222)
    - Bridgeport, City of, Department of Health (Box 10, Folder 223)
    - Brown, Philip King (Box 10, Folder 224)
    - C (Box 10, Folder 225)
    - Chapin, Charles (Box 10, Folder 226)
    - Cleanliness Institute (Box 10, Folder 227)
    - Columbia University (Box 10, Folder 228)
    - Commonwealth Fund (Box 10, Folder 229)
    - Connecticut, A-Z (Box 10, Folder 230)
    - Connecticut Society for Mental Hygiene, New Haven branch (Box 10, Folder 231)
    - Connecticut, State of (Box 10, Folder 232)
    - Connecticut, State of, Department of Health (Box 10, Folder 233)
    - D (Box 11, Folder 234)
    - Davis, Michael M. (Box 11, Folder 235)
    - Detroit, City of, Department of Health (Box 11, Folder 236)
    - E-F (Box 11, Folder 237)
    - Falk, Isidore S. (Box 11, Folder 238)
    - G (Box 11, Folder 239)
    - H-I (Box 11, Folder 240)
    - Hancock (John) Life Insurance Company (Box 11, Folder 241)
    - Health Council Executives' Association (Box 11, Folder 242)
    - J-L (Box 11, Folder 243)
    - Joint Vocational Service, Inc. (Box 11, Folder 244)
    - Los Angeles, County of (Box 11, Folder 245)
    - Los Angeles, County of, Department of Health (Box 11, Folder 246)
    - Louisville (Kentucky) Community Chest (Box 11, Folder 247)
    - M (Box 11, Folder 248)
    - Massachusetts, State of, Department of Health (Box 11, Folder 249)
    - Milbank Memorial Fund (Box 11, Folder 250)
    - N (Box 11, Folder 251)
    - National Community Center Association (Box 11, Folder 252)
    - National Conference of Social Work (Box 11, Folder 253-255)
    - National Dairy Council (Box 11, Folder 256)
    - National Organization for Public Health Nursing, Inc. (Box 11, Folder 257-258)
    - National Organization for Public Health Nursing, Inc. (Box 12, Folder 259-261)
    - National Social Work Council (Box 12, Folder 262)
    - National Society for the Prevention of Blindness, Inc. (Box 12, Folder 262)
    - National Tuberculosis Association (Box 12, Folder 262)
    - New Haven, A-Z (Box 12, Folder 263)
    - New Haven, City of, Department of Health (Box 12, Folder 264)
    - New Haven Community Chest (Box 12, Folder 265-267)
    - New Haven Council of Social Agencies (Box 12, Folder 268)
    - New Haven Organized Charities Association (Box 12, Folder 269)
    - New Haven Visiting Nurse Association (Box 12, Folder 270)
    - New York, State of, Department of Health (Box 12, Folder 271)
    - New York Tuberculosis and Health Association, Inc. (Box 12, Folder 272)
    - O (Box 12, Folder 273)
    - P (Box 12, Folder 274)
    - Q (Box 12, Folder 275)
    - R (Box 12, Folder 276)
    - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 12, Folder 277)
    - Russell Sage Foundation (Box 12, Folder 277)
    - S (Box 12, Folder 278)
    - T (Box 12, Folder 279)
    - Tennessee, State of, Department of Public Health (Box 12, Folder 280)
    - U-V (Box 13, Folder 281)
    - United States Army (Box 13, Folder 282)
    - United States Department of Agriculture (Box 13, Folder 283)
    - United States Department of Commerce (Box 13, Folder 283)
    - United States Department of the Interior (Box 13, Folder 284)
    - United States Department of Labor (Box 13, Folder 284)
    - W (Box 13, Folder 285)
    - Wesleyan University Alumni Association (Box 13, Folder 286)
    - Winslow, C.-E. A. (Box 13, Folder 287)
    - Y (Box 13, Folder 288)
    - Yale University, A-Z (Box 13, Folder 289-290)
      - Restricted (2 folders), 1929 January-December (Box 87)
    - Yale University, School of Medicine (Box 13, Folder 291-293)
  - 1929 Surveys
    - Honolulu study (Box 13, Folder 294-295)
    - Yale University Law School Bankruptcy Study (Box 13, Folder 296)
    - 1929 Writings (Box 13, Folder 297)
  - 1930 General Papers
    - A (Box 14, Folder 298)
    - American Child Health Association (Box 14, Folder 299)
    - American Public Health Association (Box 14, Folder 300-312)
    - American Public Health Association (Box 15, Folder 313)
    - American Social Hygiene Association (Box 15, Folder 314)
    - Augusta, Georgia (Box 15, Folder 315)
    - B (Box 15, Folder 316)
    - Boy Scouts of America, National Council and New Haven Council (Box 15, Folder 317)
    - Brown, Philip King (Box 15, Folder 318)
    - C (Box 15, Folder 319)
    - Committee on the Costs of Medical Care (Box 15, Folder 320)
    - Connecticut, A-Z (Box 15, Folder 321)
    - Connecticut Conference of Social Work (Box 15, Folder 322)
    - Connecticut Society for Mental Hygiene, New Haven branch (Box 15, Folder 323)
    - Connecticut, State of, Board of Education (Box 15, Folder 324)
    - Connecticut, State of, Commissioner on Domestic Animals (Box 15, Folder 324)
    - Connecticut, State of, Dairy and Food Commissioner (Box 15, Folder 324)
    - Connecticut, State of, Department of Health (Box 15, Folder 325-326)
    - D (Box 15, Folder 327)
    - Davis, Michael M. (Box 15, Folder 328)
    - Delta Omega Society (Box 15, Folder 329)
    - E-F (Box 15, Folder 330)
    - G (Box 15, Folder 331)
    - Green, Howard W. (Box 15, Folder 332)
    - Greenwich Social Service League (Box 15, Folder 333)
    - H (Box 15, Folder 334)
    - Health Council Executives' Association (Box 15, Folder 335)
    - Health Council Executives' Association (Box 16, Folder 336)
    - I (Box 16, Folder 337)
    - International Association of Dairy and Milk Inspectors (Box 16, Folder 338)
    - J (Box 16, Folder 339)
    - K-L (Box 16, Folder 340)
    - Los Angeles, County of (Box 16, Folder 341)
    - M (Box 16, Folder 342)
    - Massachusetts, State of, Department of Health (Box 16, Folder 343)
    - Milbank Memorial Fund (Box 16, Folder 344)
    - N (Box 16, Folder 345)
    - National Conference of Social Work (Box 16, Folder 346-351)
    - National Dairy Council (Box 16, Folder 352)
    - National Organization for Public Health Nursing, Inc. (Box 16, Folder 353)
    - National Organization for Public Health Nursing, Inc. (Box 17, Folder 354)
    - National Tuberculosis Association (Box 17, Folder 355)
    - New Haven, A-Z (Box 17, Folder 356)
    - New Haven Cancer Control Committee (Box 17, Folder 357-358)
    - New Haven Chamber of Commerce (Box 17, Folder 359-360)
    - New Haven Children's Community Center (Box 17, Folder 361)
    - New Haven, City of, Department of Health (Box 17, Folder 362-363)
    - New Haven Community Chest (Box 17, Folder 364-369)
    - New Haven Council of Social Agencies (Box 17, Folder 370-371)
    - New Haven First Church Home for the Aged (Box 17, Folder 372)
    - New Haven Visiting Nurse Association (Box 17, Folder 373)
    - New York, A-Z (Box 17, Folder 374)
    - New York, City of, Department of Health (Box 17, Folder 375)
    - New York, State of, Department of Health (Box 17, Folder 376)
    - O-P (Box 17, Folder 377)
    - Q-R (Box 18, Folder 378)
    - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 18, Folder 379)
    - Russell Sage Foundation (Box 18, Folder 380)
    - S (Box 18, Folder 381)
    - T (Box 18, Folder 382)
    - U (Box 18, Folder 383)
    - United States Department of Labor (Box 18, Folder 384)
    - United States Treasury Department, Public Health Service (Box 18, Folder 385)
    - V-W (Box 18, Folder 386)
    - Wesleyan University (Box 18, Folder 387)
    - White House Conference on Child Health and Protection (Box 18, Folder 388-389)
    - Winslow, Anne (Nancy) (Box 18, Folder 390)
    - Winslow, Anne R. (Mrs. C.-E. A.)
    - Winslow, C.-E. A. (Box 18, Folder 391)
    - Yale University, A-Z (Box 18, Folder 392-397)
    - Yale University Graduate School (Box 18, Folder 398)
    - Yale University, School of Medicine (Box 18, Folder 399)
    - Young Men's Christian Association (Box 18, Folder 400)
    - Young Women's Christian Association (Box 18, Folder 400)
  - 1930 Surveys
    - Cattaraugus County Health Department (Box 18, Folder 401)
    - Health and Welfare Survey of Honolulu (Box 18, Folder 402-406)
    - Public health surveys (Box 18, Folder 407)
    - San Francisco, "An Appraisal of the Public Health Program of San Francisco, California for the fiscal year 1929-1930" (Box 18, Folder 408)
    - Yale University Law School Bankruptcy Study (Box 18, Folder 409)
  - 1930 Writings (Box 18, Folder 410-412)
  - 1931 General Papers
    - A (Box 18, Folder 413)
    - American Child Health Association (Box 18, Folder 414)
    - American Epidemiological Society (Box 18, Folder 415)
    - American Public Health Association (Box 19, Folder 416-425)
    - American Social Hygiene Association (Box 20, Folder 426)
    - B (Box 20, Folder 427)
    - Bellevue-Yorkville Health Demonstration (Box 20, Folder 428)
    - Boy Scouts of America, New Haven Council (Box 20, Folder 429-431)
    - Bridgeport, Connecticut (Box 20, Folder 432)
    - C (Box 20, Folder 433)
    - Cleveland Health Council (Box 20, Folder 434)
    - Committee on the Costs of Medical Care (Box 20, Folder 435)
    - Commonwealth Fund (Box 21, Folder 436)
    - Connecticut, A-Z (Box 21, Folder 437)
    - Connecticut Conference of Social Work (Box 21, Folder 438)
    - Connecticut Public Health Association (Box 21, Folder 439)
    - Connecticut Society for Mental Hygiene, New Haven branch (Box 21, Folder 440)
    - Connecticut, State of (Box 21, Folder 441)
    - Connecticut, State of, Department of Health (Box 21, Folder 442-444)
    - D (Box 21, Folder 445)
    - Delta Omega Society (Box 21, Folder 446)
    - Detroit, City of (Box 21, Folder 447)
    - E (Box 21, Folder 448)
    - Emerson, Haven (Box 21, Folder 449)
    - F (Box 21, Folder 450)
    - Falk, Isidore S. (Box 21, Folder 451)
    - G (Box 21, Folder 452)
    - Greenwich, Connecticut (Box 21, Folder 453)
    - H (Box 21, Folder 454)
    - Hancock (John) Life Insurance Company (Box 21, Folder 455)
    - Hiscock, Margaret (Mrs. Ira V.) (Box 21, Folder 456)
    - Honolulu, Hawaii (Box 21, Folder 457)
    - I (Box 21, Folder 458)
    - International Association of Dairy and Milk Inspectors (Box 21, Folder 459)
    - J (Box 21, Folder 460)
    - K (Box 21, Folder 461)
    - L (Box 21, Folder 462)